So, here's our first trick to move a line
所以 这是我们第一个技巧来移动直线更加靠近点
closer to a point that we're going to use in linear regression.
而这个技巧将被使用在线性回归中
It's called the absolute trick,
这叫做绝对值技巧
and it works like this.
其过程如下
We start with a point and a line.
我们首先绘制一个点和直线
And the idea is that the point wants the line to come closer to it.
这个点希望直线距离更近一些
So let's put some numbers here.
所以我们在这里加入一些数字
The point has coordinates p,q where p is
这个点的坐标是 (p,q)
a horizontal coordinate and q is the vertical coordinate.
其中 p 是横坐标 q 是纵坐标
And the line has equation Y equals W1X plus W2.
这条直线的方程式为 y =W1X + W2
And here, W1 is to slope and W2 is the Y-intercept.
其中 W1 是斜率 W2 是 y 轴截距
So, an easy way to move the line closer to the point
所以这样可以很容易地移动直线 接近这个点 (p,q)
p,q is to just add one to the Y-intercept,
只需要让 y 轴截距增加 1
and then there it is. The line moves up.
然后就变成这样 这条直线向上移动
And now let's add something to the slope, too,
然后我们也增加斜率
to make the line rotate in the direction of the point.
让这条直线围绕这个点旋转
This is going to look a little strange,
这看起来有点奇怪
but it's going to make sense very soon.
不过很快就讲得通了
So, this distance over here is p because it is
所以这里的距离为 p
the horizontal distance from the Y-axis to the point.
因为这是这个点到 y 轴的水平距离
So let's just add that, let's add p to the slope.
然后我们把 p 加到斜率中
And now, our new slope is W1 plus p,
现在我们新的斜率为 W1+p
and that rotates a line in this direction.
这样按照这个方向旋转直线
Now, our new equation is Y equals W1 plus times X plus W2 plus one.
现在我们的新方程变为 y =(W1+p)x + (W2 + 1)
And that's pretty much what the absolute trick is about.
这就是绝对值技巧的具体内容
Notice some subtleties though.
不过注意一些微妙之处
Notice that we move the line a little too much,
注意我们移动直线有点过度
and we actually went over the point and kept going.
实际上我们移动到了这个点的上方 并且继续上移
We don't want this. In general in machine learning,
我们不想这样 一般来说 在机器学习中
we never want to take big steps like this.
我们永远不想像这样迈出一大步
Instead, what want to do is take tiny steps.
实际上 我们只想迈出一小步
So, in order to take a tiny step,
所以 为了迈出一小步
what we'll do we exact same thing we did except we multiply everything by a small number.
我们只能乘以一个较小的数字 才能实现我们想要的结果
So let's take a small number called a learning rate, let's say alpha,
所以我们把这个较小的数字称作学习率 即 α
and instead of adding one to the Y-intercept and p to the slope,
除了 y 轴截距加 1 斜率加 p
we will add alpha times one to the Y-intercept and alpha times p to the slope.
我们可以用 α 乘以 1 加到 y 轴截距中 α 乘以 p 加到斜率中
Now the line moves up by a little bit and rotates a little bit,
现在这条直线移动了一点 旋转了一点
so we don't have that risk of going too far.
所以我们不用担心过度的情况了
And our new equation is going to be W1 plus p times alpha times X plus W2 plus alpha.
现在我们的新方程变为 y =(W1+pα)x + (W2+α)
So, our new slope is W1 plus p times alpha,
所以我们新的斜率为 W1+pα
and our new Y-intercept is W2 plus alpha.
新的 y 轴截距为 W2+α
So we're doing better, but there's still little subtlety.
所以我们可以做的更好些 但是仍然有些细微之处
What happens if the point is not on top of the line but underneath the line?
如果这个点不在直线上方 而是在直线下方 应该怎么办呢？
Well, same thing, except now instead of adding,
好 同样的道理 并不是直接做加法
we just subtract to get our new equation,
我们只做减法 得到新的方程
W1 minus p times alpha times X plus W2 minus alpha.
y = (W1-pα)x + (W2-α)
The reason is, if we subtract alpha to the Y-intercept,
原因在于 如果我们在 y 轴截距中减去 α
the line moves down instead of up,
这条直线就会向下移动 而不是向上移动
and if we subtract p times alpha to the slope,
如果我们在斜率减去 pα
the line rotates in this direction instead.
这条直线就会向另一个方向旋转
Something even more interesting is this,
有时候更有趣的事情是这样的
and that would explain the reason p is there,
这就可以解释 p 在这儿的原因
if the point is not on the right of the Y-axis but on the left of it,
如果这个点不在 y 轴的右侧 而是在左侧
then we still add one to the Y-intercept because we need the line to move up.
那么我们还是在 y 轴截距加 1 因为我们需要让直线向上移动
But the fact that now we're adding p to the slope,
但是现在我们在斜率上加 p
and p is now a negative number,
并且现在 p 为负数
means that our line now rotates in this direction.
表明我们直线按照这个方向旋转
So, that's a reason for p to be there.
所以 p 应该位于这里
Another reason for p to be there is this.
p 位于这里还有一个原因
Check this out, if this distance is small,
检查一下 如果距离较小
then p is small, so we're adding a small number to the slope.
那么 p 也很小 所以我们在斜率上加上较小的数字
Now, if the distances is larger,
现在如果距离变大
then p is large, so we're adding a large number to the slope.
那么 p 也较大 所以我们在斜率上加上较大的数字
And it makes sense that if the point is really close to the Y-axis,
如果这个点非常靠近 y 轴 那么这就讲得通了
we want to increase the slope by a little bit,
我们想让斜率增加一点
whereas if it's far, we want to move it by a lot more.
不过如果较远 我们可以向上移动的幅度大一些
So let's do an example to make this more clear.
所以我们来看一个例子 更清楚地了解
Let's say we have the point 0.5,15 and the line Y equals 2X plus three.
我们有个点的坐标为 (5,15) 和直线 y = 2x + 3
So this means the distance from the point to the Y-axis is five.
所以这个点到 y 轴的距离为 5
Now, let's say our learning rate is 0.1.
现在如果学习率为 0.1
So we're adding 0.1 times one to the Y-intercept,
所以我们在 y 轴截距上加 0.1 乘以 1
and that moves the line up by a little bit.
让这条直接向上移动一点
Also, we're taking the five, multiplying it by 0.1
同时我们也用 5 乘以 0.1
and adding that to the slope which makes the line move in this direction.
并加到斜率中 可以让直线沿这个方向旋转
This means the new equation is Y equals 2.5X plus 3.1.
这表明新方程为 y = 2.5x + 3.1
Now check out what happens if the point is in the left.
现在如果这个点位于左侧 观察会出现什么结果
We're still adding 0.1 to the Y-intercept to move the line up.
我们还是会在 y 轴截距上加 0.1 让直线向上移动
But now to the slope,
但是现在对于斜率
we're going to add the point of 0.1 and minus five, that's minus 0.5.
我们加上 0.1 乘以 -5 的结果 即 -0.5
This means our new equation is going to be 1.5X plus 3.1.
这表明新方程为 y = 1.5x + 3.1
As you can see, the slope moved in
这样你会看到斜率向
a different direction which made it go closer to the point.
不同的方向移动 也让直线更加靠近这个点
So that's it. That's the absolute trick.
就是这样 这叫做绝对值技巧
And we're going to use it extensively in linear regression.
接下来我们会在线性回归中大量使用它